Tim Phillips, Designer

Resume

About

My name is Tim Phillips, I'm a designer with an intrinsic passion for creating intuitive digital platforms and the systems behind them.

I believe all successful projects, no matter the problem that's trying to be solved, centre around a common goal - focus on the users of the product.

Evaluating how users both perceive and interact with a system helps guide the choices I make when designing the tangible interfaces of a product.

Throughout my process, I work horizontally across research, design and engineering, allowing me to constantly adapt and iterate to ensure the final outcome is tested and proven.

While I believe I have a strong skillset as a designer, I'm a lifelong learner and constantly strive to develop and expand my UI and UX methodologies in an effort to grow as a designer.

Contact

Email: timphillips1991@gmail.com

Web: timphillipsdesign.com.au

Phone: +61 409 888 443

Education

Bachelor of Design, Communication Design Swinburne University of Technology 2012

Diploma of Graphic Design Swinburne University of Technology 2010 - 2011

Skills

Product Design, with a focus on user experience and design systems. Frontend engineering: HTML, CSS, JavaScript. React and Svelte frameworks.

Employment

Assembler (2020 - present)

I work as the Lead Product Designer for Assembler. Leading the design across their Dashboard, App Builder and App Manager platforms, as well as the Assembler design system. I also support the engineering team with front-end web development.

PwC Australia (2018 - 2020)

Working within PwC Australia's New Ventures unit, I led the design and front-end web development within the *Automation Engine* venture, a platform used by internal teams to build web applications.

Just Group (2017 - 2018)

Predominantly worked on the Smiggle brand, designing web and email content for their global market base (AU, UK, IRE and Asia). Also working across the Just Group's other core brands in varying capacities.

General Assembly (2016)

Upon completing the Front-End Web Development (FEWD) course at General Assembly, I was invited to work as an Instructional Assistant for their upcoming FEWD course.

Web123 (2015-2016)

Working with a broad range of small to medium business clients, I delivered web design, front-end development and brand design services across a variety of local industries.

Earlier Experience (2012-2015)
Graphic Communications,
MP Joanne Ryan, Federal Parliment

Junior Graphic Designer, Simm Design, Design Studio

Freelance Design, ICHPIG, Clothing Brand